Guide to the Michael La Vean French documents collection, 1751-1851
George Mason University Libraries
- Michael La Vean French documents collection
  - Letter from Sub-Prefect of Pontivy to Mayor of Lominé Re: Request for details about existing primary school facilities, teachers, etc. 10 Prairial, year 11 (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - Copy of a letter from the Sub-prefect of Morbihan Re: Authorisation for Etienne Seguin, gunsmith, to buy up any guns presented to him 11 Prairial, year 11 (Box 5, Folder 206)
    Letter; 16 x 20.5 cm
  - Letter from Sub-Prefect of Pontivy to Mayor of Lominé requesting more information Re: town dues 12 Prairial, year 11 (Box 5, Folder 207)
    Letter ;11.5 x 19.5
  - Record of the criminal court of Morbihan Re: charges of infanticide against Louise le Bourdal 15 Prairial, year 11 (Box 5, Folder 208)
    Letter ;20.5 x 24 cm
  - Letter 182 from the Sub-Prefect of the Arrondissement of Pontivy to Mayor of Lominé Re: monetary abuses 25 Prairial, year 11 (Box 5, Folder 209)
    Letter ;11.5 x 19 cm
    Signed [D'Haucouz]
  - Letter from the Sub-Prefect of the Arrondissement of Pontivy to the Mayor of Lominé Re: counterfeit money 17 Messidor, year 11 (Box 5, Folder 210)
    Letter ;12 x 19.5 cm
  - Letter from the Sub-Prefect of Pontivy to the Mayor of Lominé Re: Additional account of civil acts during the complementary days to be added to the table documenting population shift 17 Messidor, year 11 (Box 5, Folder 211)
    Letter ;12.5 x 20.5 cm
  - Letter from the President of the Criminal Court of Morbihan to Lominé Mayors and Deputies Re: Forwarded copy of a judgement acquitting Louise le Bourda[t] of infanticide. 17 Thermidor, year 11 (Box 5, Folder 212)
    Letter ;20 x 24 cm
  - Letter 91 from the Sub-Prefect of Pontivy to the Mayor of Lominé requesting the number of people conscripted for the English war. 5th complementary day, year 11 (Box 5, Folder 213)
  - Patterson's Road: A new and accurate description of all the direct and principal crossroads in England and Wales and parts of the roads of Scotland. 1811 (Box 7)
    Book ;not known
  - Letter from the Sub-Prefect of Pontivy to Mayor of Lominé Re: Notification of pension statement 7th Frimaire, year 12 (Box 5, Folder 214)
    signed D'Haucouz
  - Letter from Mayor of Pont de la Liberté to the Mayor of Lominé Re: Request for certification of death for Giles Henri Sommelier and Elisabeth ... 29 Frimaire, year 12 (Box 5, Folder 215)
    Letter ;19 x 25 cm
  - Letter from the Prefect of Morbihan to the Mayor of Loeminé Re: Pension for Monsieur l'abbé Richard. 28 Thermidor, year 12 (Box 5, Folder 216)
    Letter ;18.5 x 25.5 cm
    signed Jullien, General of the Brigade, Prefect of Morbihan
  - Report from the Mayor of Loeminé Re: repairs authorized to be made in the chapel of the congregation 23 Fructidor, year 12 (Box 5, Folder 217)
    report ;18 x 25.5 cm
  - Record of the minutes of the secretary of state Re: the redistribution of communally held property 9 Brumaire, year 13 (Box 5, Folder 218)
    manuscript official minutes from St. Cloud ;22 x 35.5 cm
  - Letter from Mathurin le [Poteevin] to Commissioner of Locminé Re: Request for reparations for damage done before the war by the chouans; 24 Prairial, year 13 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    Letter ;18.5 x 23.5
    signed Le Tubro for the petitioner
  - Bulletin of laws and initiatives by Emperor 30 Frimaire, year 14 (Box 5, Folder 220)
    Letter ;14.5 x 22
    Organization of local government; hospices, patents; printed
  - From the register of correctional police Re: Arrest and sentencing of François Tanguy for stealing a sack of grain 19 février 1806 (Box 5, Folder 221)
    Register ;20.5 x 32.5 cm
  - Notice of an Imperial Decree 9 January, 1807 (Box 5, Folder 222)
    notice ;21.5 x 25 cm
    List of citizens over 21 with qualifications and exclusions
  - Letter from M. Debroise to the Mayor of Rennes Re: Official notice of change of residence from Rennes to Lominé 14 march, 1807 (Box 5, Folder 223)
  - Letter from President of criminal court of Morbihan to the Mayor and Deputy Mayors of Locminé Re: aquittal of Julien Bartholomi Picar[rd], resident of Locminé 12 [ ] 1807 (Box 5, Folder 224)
  - Letter from the Sub-Prefect of Napoléonville to Mayor of Lominé Re: The people of Lominé were not showing proper reverence for Napoléon in church 7, 180[7] (Box 5, Folder 225)
    Letter ;44 x 19 cm
    signed Le Bare
  - Letter from Vanne Le Mou [hit moring] a M. [l'ami] warning him of intrigue concerning the friend. 30 September, 1807 (Box 5, Folder 226)
    Letter ;17 x 21 cm
    signed.
  - Sample account book printed in Draguignan Re: communal finances 1807 (Box 5, Folder 227)
    account book ;20.5 x 25.5 cm
  - Notice from President of the criminal court, Morbihan, to Mayor and Deputies of Locminé Re: Warrant for arrest and condemnation of Mathurin P[epion], resident of Locminé 7 January, 1808 (Box 5, Folder 228)
    Notice ;20 x 25 cm
  - Extract from the registry of domiciliary and political affiliation Re: Pierre le Guéré is transfering his political rights as a citizen from Languidic to Locminé 28 April, 1810 (Box 5, Folder 229)
    government record ;21 x 29.5 cm
  - Official notice from Napoléon Re: Indictment and sentencing of Armand Maison, Gendarme, for shooting of fugitive Louis Rio. 18 [J], 1810 (Box 5, Folder 230)
    Notice; 22.5 x 31 cm
    official stamp affixed, last page; silver flecks in ink
  - Letter No. 190 from Sub-Prefect of Napoléonville to Lominé Re: A request for an updated list of citizens of Lominé who have reached the age of 21 since the last list and who no longer live there to be given to the town hall 18 august, 1812 (Box 5, Folder 231)
    Letter ;13 x 18 cm
  - From the Prefecture of Morbihan to the Mayors of the Department Re: Letter concerning the election of officials -specifically the place - not to interrupt church services. 18 September, 1812 (Box 5, Folder 232)
    Printed letter ;19 x 24 cm
    printed
  - Note from an associate of M. Louault Re: a girl who caused trouble for the owner of the papers - [Baullée] after [17 germinal, 1813] (Box 5, Folder 233)
    Note ;12.5 x 19 cm
  - Letter from the district court of Napoléonville asking for candidates named by the local assembly to be justice of the peace with an account of their qualifications to fill vacancy. 27 march, 1813 (Box 6, Folder 234)
    Tahien
  - Letter from the Mayor of Locminé to the civil court of Napoléonville Re: List of names of candidates named by local assembly to be justice of the peace. 31 march, 1813 (Box 6, Folder 235)
  - Medal of Saint Helena awarded to Pierre Berthe, former soldier with Stamp of the Imperial order of the Legion of Honor 5 may, 1821 (Box 6, Folder 236)
    Certificate ;29.5 x 19.5 cm
    small crusty patch in center
  - Recruitment poster from the Sub-prefect of Brignoles telling when and where drawings will be held. 14 February, 1822 (Box 6, Folder 237)
    poster ;30.5 x 38 cm
  - Record of the meeting of the agricultural committee of Pontivy regarding prizes for the most distinguished farmers at the great livestock fair. 6 April, 1823 (Box 6, Folder 238)
    Government record ;20.5 x 31.5 cm
  - Notice from the committee of agriculture regarding agricultural (bull and beekeeping) competitions 20 July, 1824 (Box 6, Folder 239)
    Notice ;18 x 27.5 cm
  - Recruitment notice from the Prefect of War with date and time of the drawing of the names of new recruits 1 February, 1826 (Box 8, Folder 240)
    Notice; 30.5 x 38 cm
  - Account of a decision of separate maintenance - séparation de biens - of Mathurin Marie Guillon marchand in Locminé and Dame Perrine. 11 Floréal 1838 (Box 6, Folder 241)
    Civil court document ;17.5 x 25 cm
    signed Carelo, Pontivy; 2 x timbre royal
  - Draft of notice from administrators of Vannes to Sub-Prefect of Pontivy and the Minister of Education Re: Decision to build a primary school in the back of the church. date uncertain - [1839] (Box 6, Folder 242)
    notice; 18.5 x 28 cm
  - Record of a military judgement of the 2nd division of Mezières Re: Condemnation of a superior. 14 September, 1842 (Box 6, Folder 243)
    Military court record ;20 x 31 cm
    signed Montimeau
  - Letter from Office of War in Pontivy to the Mayor of Locminé enclosing a military court's verdict and notifying the family of the condemned, Pierre-Marie-Granet, resident of the commune. 22 December, 1843 (Box 6, Folder 244)
    Letter ;19.75 x 20.5 cm
  - Letter from the Sub-prefecture of Pontivy to the Mayor of Locminé; Forwarded act of judgement against Fablet, Jean-Louise, for 2 years in prison. 12 December, 1844 (Box 6, Folder 245)
    Letter ;18 x 22 cm
  - Court record from Pontivy in Morbihan Re: Dispute between Buleon, Kelan[d], Lervio in cabaret; with a sum to be paid. 26 January, 1849 (Box 6, Folder 246)
    Letter ;19.5 x 30 cm
    signed Alphonse de Broise, justice of the peace
  - Statement of criminal conviction in Locminé 1 April, 1851 (Box 6, Folder 247)
    Court document ;17.5 x 25
    Signed Thomazin, "procureur" and [Léguy], clerk of the court
  - Statement of criminal conviction from Locminé Re: 2 months prison to Louis Marie Eget for theft. 29 April 1851 (Box 6, Folder 248)
    court document ;17.5 x 25 cm
    Re: signed Thomazin, procurator, and W [] clerk of the court
  - Statement of criminal conviction from Pontivy of Bihan, Antoine, day-laborer: sentenced to 4 months prison for thefts. 29 April, 1851 (Box 6, Folder 249)
    court record ;17.5 x 25 cm
    signed Thomazin and W[ondenbeselhe] clerk of the court
  - Personal correspondence Re: Monseigneur Dubreuil, Evéque de Vannes; no letterhead. no date (Box 6, Folder 250)
    draft of letter ;15.5 x 20.5
  - Letter 7 copy from Anne de Bruchec to Commissioner of restitution with amount of cash and goods stolen by the chouans. no date - after an 3 (Box 6, Folder 251)
    Letter ;19 x 23 cm
  - Small label for a dossier of 16 "pièces" Re: political residency. no date (Box 6, Folder 252)
    small scrap ;8.5 x 4.5 cm
  - Letter from Cosmé Brien[s] to National Convention Re: pillaged by 50 brigands several times. Between 179... - 17.... (Box 6, Folder 253)
    Letter; 17.5 x 20 cm
  - Copy of the letter signed by the engineer of Morbihan to administration of Morbihan Re: Plan to verify the spending for aligning the crossroads in Lominé. no date (Box 6, Folder 254)
    Letter ;18.5 x 28 cm
  - Letter from Baud to Lominé stating that Be[luillet] is object of suspicion for chouannerie. no date (Box 6, Folder 255)
    Letter ;16 x 20 cm
    signed Boll[ay] et alias
  - Extrait de registre; model Re: Transfer of political rights from one commune to another; models 2-5. no date (Box 6, Folder 256)
    print model or example ;20.5 x 24.5 cm
  - Blank Public record model From Morbihan: Transfer of political rights from one commune to another; printed; model 6. no date (Box 6, Folder 257)
    print model or example ;20 x 24 cm
  - Record to be kept in civic register according to Mayor of Locminé. no date; maybe after 1806 (Box 6, Folder 258)
    government record ;19.5 x 31 cm
    Blank record; signed Nanzegal, Mayor and Louis Ammé Allaire
  - Notice from the Mayor of Locminé Re: Battallion of 10th regiment of infantry to be housed at the expense of those invited to host them. no date (Box 6, Folder 259)
    manuscript draft of official notice ;19.5 x 15.5 cm
    Note on reverse Re: lost sum of money.
  - Cover pages for lists no date (Box 6, Folder 260)
    Official document template ;20 x 30 cm
    Page titles: political residency, judgement; members of electoral college; division of state property; blank pages.